<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Priya Mishra</title>
    <link>https://priya2698.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://priya2698.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Priya Mishra</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://priya2698.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Priya Mishra</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>De-biasing Autonomous Vehicle Data</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/project/av_bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/project/av_bias/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started working with Dr. Fiodar Kazhamiaka in the Future Data Systems Lab, led by Prof. Matei Zaharia on removing sampling bias in data collected from autonomous vehicles. For more info on this work, check out their &lt;a href=&#34;https://cs.stanford.edu/~fiodar/pubs/avquery-cidr21.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;position paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meerkat: DataPanels for Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/project/meerkat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/project/meerkat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently working in the Hazy Research Lab led by Prof. Chris Re on the Meerkat project. Meerkat is a new data library for machine learning datasets that allows easier interaction with data across various modalities. I implemented an ML module to integrate Meerkat with PyTorch, Lightning and Huggingface models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication-aware Job Scheduling using SLURM</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/publication/communication-aware-job-scheduling-using-slurm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/publication/communication-aware-job-scheduling-using-slurm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Disaggregation</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/project/energy-disaggregation-using-optimization-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/project/energy-disaggregation-using-optimization-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with Prof. Denis Trystram and collaborated with Qarnot, a green cloud computing company, to design an energy disaggregation algorithm for their smart buildings. The Qarnot Computing platform uses computing-heaters and utilizes the waste heat from IT computations in their buidings and offices. Through energy disaggregation, our aim was to better understand the energy requirements at different locations of the building and hence, forecast energy needs. Using this information, we can achieve a more efficient job scheduling, for example, scheduling more jobs where there is greater energy requirement. We developed an integer linear programming approach using the information provided by Qarnot Computing about different devices used in their offices and buildings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving Scheduling using Job Runtime Predictions</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/project/improving-scheduling-using-job-runtime-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/project/improving-scheduling-using-job-runtime-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with Prof. Denis Trystram on studying the impact of job runtime estimates on the performance of non-clairoyant scheduling algorithms. More specifically, we considered the problem of scheduling a set of independent jobs whose processing times are unknown. User runtimes are known to be highly inaccurate. Scheduling policies such as backfilling or shortest job first rely on these estimates to schedule jobs. In this work, we explored the use of machine learning methods to provide better estimates for the exceution times using user history and job characteristics. Instead of estimating the exact value of the job runtime, we consider that the jobs fall in two categories &amp;ndash; short and long jobs and predict the type of each job. We used several classification models as well as simpler schemes such as predicting based on the class of previously submitted jobs alone. We evaluated our models using several full workload traces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication-aware Job Scheduling using SLURM</title>
      <link>https://priya2698.github.io/project/communication-aware-job-scheduling-using-slurm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://priya2698.github.io/project/communication-aware-job-scheduling-using-slurm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I worked with Prof. Preeti Malakar on improving the performance of communication-intensive jobs on high performance clusters or supercomputers.
Jobs submitted to clusters or supercomputers vary in resource requirements and execution times. Increasingly, they also vary in other characteristics such as communication and I/O behavior. Most of the current job-schedulers do not consider the communication characteristics of a job which leads to sub-optimal allocations.
We implemented three new node-allocation algorithms, greedy, balanced and adaptive which consider the communication characteristics of the submitted jobs and proposed a novel way of optimizing node-allocation based on underlying algorithms of MPI collectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional details can be found in the paper: &lt;a href=&#34;https://priya2698.github.io/publication/communication-aware-job-scheduling-using-slurm/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Communication-aware Job Scheduling using SLURM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
